Like living in a dreamland
Magical powers gifted to me
From the pocket full of treasures
Traveling together across the cosmos
Catching atop the Milky Way
The beauty of time
Whenever we run into trouble
Anytime, anywhere, ideas burst to life
Fly swiftly to a carefree wonderland
Hand in hand with starlight
Dancing and shining bright
Step right through this door
To make our dreams come true
Crossing over railways and fields
In a flash, the dream express appears
Sha-la-la-la-la
Singing along with me
Shouting encores loud
Stepping to the beat together
Doraemon
Make this moment last forever
Our dreams will come true at last
Sha-la-la-la-la
Singing along with me
Shouting encores loud
Stepping to the beat together
Doraemon
Make this moment last forever
The wonderful view will be right before our eyes
"Human Locomotive"
Who's number five?
I'm number five!
Lucky!
I'm paired up with Dekisugi!
I drew number seven
I'm number seven too
Looks like my luck isn't so great
Get ready
- One, two...
Why aren't you matching my pace?
You said right foot first!
Stop making excuses!
Help me!
Is the three-legged race really supposed to be like this?
Hey
What are you doing?
There's a three-legged race at tomorrow's sports day
You mean... Nobita and Gian are in the same group?
I'm done practicing
There's no way we can win like this
I was just thinking the same thing
I know
You, drop out of the three-legged race
That way...
...won't my partner have to be replaced?
What if I don't drop out?
Then you should know what'll happen
How can you be like that?
What's wrong, Nobita? Are you okay?
He said he'll beat me up if I don't drop out!
What now? What do you want me to do?
Gian just runs way too fast
Is there any way that I can
run as fast as Gian too?
In that case...
"Human Locomotive Set"
A locomotive?
That's right
This is called a steam locomotive
It runs on coal as fuel
powered by steam generated from burning coal
It has tremendous power and bursts of energy
and it's packed with speed
Which, compared to you, Nobita...
is pretty much the exact opposite
Sorry...
Put on this smokestack
Just eat some coal, then drink some water
Here
Here, water
How is it?
Around my belly button...
it's starting to heat up
Incredible!
Power is surging out non-stop!
I can't stand still anymore!
Why don't you try running?
Okay!
This is awesome!
I'm back!
You're back? How was it?
It's seriously amazing!
Gian will definitely be shocked when he sees this!
Shizuka, what are you doing?
I have piano lessons, and I'm going to be late!
If I take you, you won't be late!
Huh? You'll take me?
Doraemon!
Alright
Is this really going to be okay?
Leave it to me!
Train, moving out!
How is it? Doesn't this feel great?
There's so much smoke!
What? Go even faster?
Alright!
Are you kidding me?
Shizuka, we're almost there!
Really?
Ah, we're here!
Well? Made it in time, didn't we?
I guess so...
Oh dear, my laundry is completely covered in soot!
Mine too!
That's so awful!
Tell me about it
I just hope Nobita doesn't get carried away
- One, two...
Hey, have you seen Gian?
Nope
We clearly had a chance to take first place
- One, two...
No way
First place is ours
This is the ultimate combination
of good looks and genius
That's for sure!
If that's what you think, I'll show you
Show us what?
No idea
Make sure you hold on tight
Locomotive Nobita, departing now!
Nobita!
Nobita, what's wrong?
- Woah, it's so hot...
- This is bad!
Oh no, Nobita!
- Water...
That was awful just now
I need to find Gian right away
Thanks for your business!
Gian!
Let's practice the three-legged race together
Practicing is completely pointless
All you have to do is drop out
Just calm down
Wait until you see how I run before saying that
That's it then
Wait...
That's strange
Why's that?
It must be because it got soaked in water earlier
All right, I'll eat up all the leftover coal
and crank it to full power
Nobita, that's very rude
Teacher!
Huh? What is it, Nobita?
N-Nothing's wrong
Your face looks really red
Do you have a fever?
Oh?
Woah, you're burning up! You need to go to the hospital right away
Nobita!
Gian!
Hurry up and...
practice...
You're such a pain
What do you want?
Fine... you win
I'll practice with you for a bit
No amount of practice will help
You can't keep up with my speed anyway
Get ready
- One, two...
Looks like you can run pretty fast
I can go even faster!
You're running pretty well too
We can go even faster!
Wait!
Stop!
How's that?
Now you know how powerful I am
So powerful...
I can't stop!
Stop!
- One, two...
- Get out of the way!
- Nobita!
Hey, Nobita!
Where on earth is Nobita?
Help me!
We can't stop!
This is bad!
Nobita, stop!
Get out of the way!
It's no good
Cape of Protection!
Doraemon!
It stopped
Doraemon, what about Nobita and Gian?
Gian is safe at last
Here comes Nobita!
Retrieving Lasso, hurry and catch Nobita!
It worked!
- Pull!
- Right
Nobita has gotten so strong
He's basically a runaway locomotive!
He won't stop until all his coal burns out
But if this keeps up...
All right
Wait for me, Nobita!
A person?
Don't run away!
Nobita!
A raccoon-dog locomotive?
Don't run away!
So close!
Great!
Stop!
All right, I have to stop you no matter what
Hey, Nobita, stop!
There's a cliff ahead!
Oh no, I can't stop in time!
Not this one...
Something to make the locomotive stop...
This is the one!
Haha, awesome!
(Terminal Stop)
That's wonderful, Nobita...
Doraemon?
A cliff? The sea?
This is so frustrating!
Gian
Woah, Nobita!
Now you know how fast I am!
I'll definitely win first place at tomorrow's sports day!
I'm planning to...
sit out
But...
Save your breath, I'm definitely sitting out
Don't say that
Please, just leave!
There's really nothing to be done
"Matsutake Hunting in a Miniature Landscape"
Yesterday I went to a matsutake mountain
Found it...
Awesome!
Grilling freshly picked matsutake
over charcoal
enjoying the aroma
and then savoring its flavor...
It's the ultimate treat!
Eating matsutake you picked yourself
really is especially delicious
Why don't you guys try
going to pick some delicious matsutake too?
But you don't have much spare cash
so you probably won't get the chance
That Suneo...
It's so annoying when he shows off
Though it really does make you jealous
In that case
I'll ask Doraemon!
Come on, even with Doraemon's pocket
there's no way he has a whole matsutake mountain in there
Mom, please!
Even if it's just once in my life
please take me matsutake picking!
As the old saying goes, matsutake for aroma
shimeji for flavor
Shimeji mushrooms taste way better than matsutake
One, two...
Oh, you're back?
Autumn's hearty appetite is such a headache
It's so easy to gain weight
Are you all right? Why the long face?
Mom says shimeji mushrooms taste better
When I really wanted to eat matsutake!
Oh, is that all? That's simple then
"Gourmet Tablecloth"
An all-matsutake meal!
That's not it!
I want to pick them myself like Suneo
and eat the matsutake right on the spot!
What a jerk!
It's so annoying, but I'm so jealous too
What's the matter with Dad?
A friend of mine told me
he caught a char fish this big!
And...
That just proves
there's a huge gap in fishing skill between us
If you won't admit defeat, let's see you catch one too!
It makes me so mad!
If I went, I definitely would have caught one!
It's just that I couldn't go because I was too busy
In that case, why not go to the fishing center over there?
A fishing pond?
But wild char are only found
in deep mountain streams!
I want to challenge the unpredictable mountain streams!
A man's romance is fishing for char in a mountain stream!
Wild char, freshly caught...
...tastes best salt-grilled over charcoal right away
I really want to go
We've got that!
We really have a mountain stream!
"Artificial Bonsai Series: Mountain Stream"
An artificial bonsai? What's it for?
Once you turn it on...
...the water circulates to form a stream
Then you put these
Miniature Instant-Growth Fish Eggs into the bonsai
What's going to happen?
Nothing's happening
There we go!
Dad, go get your fishing gear ready!
I've got everything packed and changed into my gear
Small Light!
Hold on tight, Dad!
1003634
This is amazing!
1005047
And there are so many fish!
1008270
Have fun fishing here!
1010397
Thank you, Doraemon!
1012408
It'd be bad if someone kicked it
1013774
So let's leave it here
1015792
Hey, you said this was the Artificial Bonsai Series earlier
1018767
Does that mean there are other kinds of mountains?
1020973
Of course there are
1022374
There's Rocky Mountain for rock climbing practice
1026594
Long Ski Mountain for skiing
1029314
Hiking Mountain, perfect for kids
1031773
And Adventure Mountain, full of thrills!
1035083
With so many mountains, there probably isn't a matsutake mushroom mountain
1037681
Of course there is!
1038773
Really?
1040418
"Bonsai Series: Red Pine Mountain for Matsutake Gathering"
1043277
Red pine?
1044356
That's right. In fact, typical matsutake mushrooms
1046329
mostly grow on the roots of red pine trees
1049055
by propagating their mycelium
1052129
Sprinkle the matsutake mycelium...
1054826
add just the right amount of sunlight and rain...
1057147
and they'll grow in about ten minutes
1061039
In that case...
1061958
We have to invite Shizuka!
1065384
You want to go pick matsutake mushrooms now?
1067343
Yeah, and it's all-you-can-pick and all-you-can-eat!
1070015
Just come check it out first
1071800
Small Light!
1078766
This mountain is magnificent!
1079906
It sure is
1081159
Where do you think they'll be?
1082799
Let's start searching on the south side of the mountain
1085707
Matsutake mushrooms grow more easily
1088240
in sunny spots with good ventilation
1091183
It's so reassuring having Doraemon around
1094809
This path is pretty steep
1102817
Nobita, are you okay?
1104790
I'm fine!
1107270
Right over there! There are lots of red pines!
1110960
Alright
1113078
I have to pick them myself!
1117393
These are the red pines
1119495
Little matsutake
1120812
My mistake, Mr. Matsutake
1122730
Where on earth are you?
1124558
I don't see any around here
1126800
Where's the best place to look?
1129482
I think it's best to look up
1131452
from the bottom of the slope as you search
1134245
First check the roots of the red pines, then circle around
1137328
They say pine tree roots spread out
1139416
over a very wide area
1143653
Hey, Mr. Matsutake
1145072
Mr. Matsutake, where are you?
1151868
Oh no!
1153086
Help me!
1156310
What should I do? Should I play dead?
1158458
No, get to higher ground!
1163551
Help me!
1165571
Nobita, hurry and get up higher!
1167965
Easy for you to say! How do I get up there?
1171889
Nobita!
1175289
1176417
Help me!
1178710
Go to the other side of the mountain!
1188706
Alright
1191705
Caught one!
1195774
Where could they be?
1197367
Please let me find one
1198882
Alright, I have to find one this time!
1200940
Matsutake... where on earth are you?
1203299
He said to look up from the bottom earlier
1207828
Found it!
1209242
It's a matsutake!
1213581
It really is!
1214513
-Yay!
1216034
But how do I pick it when it's up so high?
1222999
Then let's use the Bamboo Copter
1224908
You can't do that!
1225682
Matsutake only taste so good because they're hard to pick!
1229484
Nobita!
1235723
-Nobita!
-You can do it!
1237868
Shizuka!
1239934
I'll do my best!
1242426
Almost got it!
1247488
I did it!
1248496
Nobita!
1258052
Smells so good!
1259503
It's not fair that Nobita gets to smell it all by himself!
1265589
What is it this time?
1269653
What is that?
1279011
Huh, that's strange?
1280411
Shizuka was definitely just here
1283142
How are you doing, Nobita?
1284143
Are you alright?
1285076
I'm fine
1286004
The matsutake are more important!
1287729
Doraemon, look!
1289589
There are so many matsutake here!
1292220
It's a huge matsutake!
1293780
They're everywhere!
1295199
There's so many matsutake growing!
1296846
Mr. Matsutake!
1299352
-Yay, so many matsutake...
-There are so many matsutake...
1301605
Yay...
1304067
What should I make for dinner tonight?
1308936
Oh, they have matsutake
1314469
T-Ten thousand yen?
1320851
Picking this many should be enough
1323738
Now then, it's time for
1325135
the charcoal-grilled matsutake we've all been waiting for!
1328375
-Yay!
-Awesome!
1330142
If you wash matsutake too much, they'll lose their fragrance
1333273
So just gently wipe them clean with a damp cloth
1336396
Then tear them apart by hand
1338038
And then you can grill them on the charcoal stove!
1340681
But...
1342109
I've already prepared some
freshly grilled matsutake right here!
1351702
It smells so good!
1355259
Mr. Matsutake, don't mind if I do
1362348
-Delicious!
-So delicious!
1364094
This is what
1365194
freshly hand-picked hard work tastes like!
1368674
It's truly delicious!
1375286
I'm so full!
1376550
Yeah
1377450
Enlarge Flashlight
1381803
The matsutake mushrooms got bigger!
1383631
I wonder how Dad is doing?
1390383
I caught so many fish!
1393061
Looks like Dad had a great catch too!
1395030
Awesome!
1396260
I'm home!
1398040
Huh?
1400279
The aroma of matsutake?
1402005
How could that be?
1403372
We don't even have that kind of food at home
1409526
-Mom, you're back?
1412813
You're all here?
1414613
Look, this is tonight's dinner!
1416693
It's freshly picked matsutake!
1419071
And wild char that I caught, look!
1424961
Matsutake, and... and char?
1428520
That's impossible!
1430720
I must be dreaming
1432719
It's real, you're not dreaming!
1435078
Hurry and make dinner!
1437139
No way... this can't be real!
1438866
Something's wrong with me, I must still be half-asleep!
1441360
I already told you it's real!
1442967
I want to eat delicious matsutake rice
1444795
and super savory salt-grilled char!
1447468
No way... I refuse to believe a dream like this!
1452568
Sha-la-la-la-la
1454155
Sing along with me
1456681
Shout for an encore
1458088
Stepping along together in joy
1460701
Doraemon
1461969
Keeping this moment young forever
1463981
Beautiful sights will come into view